# **Declan Greenhalgh**

http://www.decln.com Email: dec@decln.com

#### Who I am

I am a software developer working at ION Trading Ltd., developing software solutions in the FX space. I am currently working on a large-scale FX re-engineering project that utilises Java and SQL technologies (alongside the proprietary ION technologies), though I am equally keen on working with C# and Python.

I have followed an atypical route into software development/management, having come from a psychology background prior to my computer science education. This background complements my skills in software engineering, with my main interests being in organisational capabilities, Agile practices and development processes - all contributing to regular delivery of high value change.

I aim to continue growing in an technical application management role, but still want to preserve my technical skills. Potential career paths that interest me include enterprise architecture and developer management, but in these early stages of my career I would like to get a variety of experiences.

## **Employment**

## ION Trading Ltd.,

Developer (February '18 - Present)

- > Working on a large-scale, multi-year FX trade management re-engineering project.
- ➤ Use of TDD automation frameworks (e.g., Robot Framework) and large scale scrum (LeSS).
- > Focus on delivering SOA components forming part of the FX post-trade solution.

## NatWest Markets (Royal Bank of Scotland Group)

Application Manager / Developer - Associate (September '17 - February '18)

- > Worked primarily in an application management/developer role in the Futures Technology space.
- Day-to-day was working on the in-house Futures Execution & Clearing Order Management System that handles execution and allocation routing between the full F2B stack. Have previously worked on a major transformation project due to a 3<sup>rd</sup>-party vendor switch, working on the entire lifecycle in an agile environment. Currently working on MiFID II project deliverables.
- > Have been responsible for the implementation of CMMI within my application.
- > Technologies used include Java, FIX Protocol, Oracle SQL, Unix, TIBCO EMS, IBM MQ and a variety of agile tools.
- > Focus on application design, project management, stakeholder management, and providing services as the application SME.

# MThree Consulting Ltd / NatWest Markets

Developer (September 2015 – September 2017)

> As above, however in a more junior capacity and as a third party resource.

## **University of Kent Information Services**

Assistant Support Desk Supervisor (September 2014 – August 2015)

- > Role included supervisory & SME aspects.
- Required to manage the University IT services at the weekend and out of hours.

IT and Library Support Desk Assistant (April 2013 – September 2014)

- Customer-facing helpdesk role helping with technical issues.
- > Helped develop my abilities to deal with a range of customers, communicating with relevant colleagues and maintaining a presentable, professional work environment.

#### Education

## MSc. Computer Science, University of Kent, 2014 - 2015

Obtained a Master's degree in a programme covering a wide range of computing concepts, including: Java-based Object Oriented Programming, Web-Based Information Systems, Logic Programming, Machine Learning and Systems Architecture.

### BSc. (Hons.) Psychology and Sociology, University of Kent, 2011-2014

Obtained a 2:1. Undertook two research projects in my final year, including a technical-based electroencephalography study in Psychology.

## Lancaster Royal Grammar School, 2005-2011

Obtained an 'A' grade in History, and 'B' grades in Chemistry, French, Drama and General Studies A-Levels. Gained 12 GCSEs A\*-C, including English Literature (A\*), English Language (A) and Maths (A).

#### **Professional Affiliations:**

- > British Psychological Society, with a title of MBPsS. Part of the Division of Occupational Psychology.
- ➤ British Computing Society, with the title of AMBCS. Member of additional Specialist Groups including Software Process Improvement Network, Software Practice Advancement, Agile Methods, Financial Services and Advanced Programming.

#### **Additional Information & Interests**

- I enjoy playing the piano in my spare time.
- > Treasurer and committee member of the University's trampolining team for two years.
- British Gymnastics' qualified judge, and have judged at national competitions to an elite level.
- Received Green Colours from Kent Sport for the administrative service I provided to the club.